metaio.com 2016-04-12

# 

www.metaio.com
                                                                      Privacy Policy
metaio GmbH (“metaio”) provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and
procedures regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of the information that we collect
and receive from users of the metaio website (the “Site”), metaio products (the
“Products”) and the metaio Developer Portal (collectively the “Services”). This Privacy
Policy applies only to information that you provide to us through the Services. This
Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. We will notify you of any material
changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on the Site. You are advised to consult this
policy regularly for any changes.
As used in this policy, the terms “using” and “processing” information include using
cookies on a computer or a mobile device, subjecting the information to statistical or other
analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to
collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and
transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within the United
States or internationally.
By using the metaio Services, you consent to the collection, use, disclosure, transfer,
storage and other such uses of the information collected as described under this Privacy
Policy. This consent is valid regardless of how you are using the metaio Services and
regardless of residence or where information is being shared from.
Information Collection and Use
Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Services and
to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate the Services.
Personal Information. When using our Services, we may ask that you provide us with
some personally identifiable information – information about you that can be used to
contact or identify you, and information on your use or potential use of the Services and
related services (“Personal Information”). Personal Information that we might collect
includes information like your name, email address, and your work and home address.
Personal Information may also include other information you supply to us concerning your
preferences and interests expressed in the course of using the Services.
We use Personal Information for the following purposes: (i) to administer the Services,
(ii) to enable users to easily navigate the Services, (iii) to provide, improve and optimize
the Services, (iv) to better understand users needs and interests, (iv) to personalize your
experience, (v) to provide you with software updates and/or product announcements, and
(vi) to provide you with further information and offers from us that we believe you may find
useful or interesting.
Usage Information. When you use certain Services, our servers will automatically record
information that you send or transmit, including, but not limited to, the model and device
ID number of your mobile device, user settings, location and information about your use
© 2015 metaio GmbH • Worldwide: +49 89 5480 198-0 • USA: +1 415 814-3376 • email: info@metaio.com
All information contained in this document is confidential and proprietary

www.metaio.com
of the Services (“Usage Information”). We use this information to provide and improve
the Services, develop new products, and offer products and services that may be of
interest to you.
Log Data. When you visit or use the Site, our servers automatically record information
that your browser sends whenever you visit a website (“Log Data”). This Log Data may
include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser
type or the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Site, pages of our Site that
you visit, the time spent on those pages, information you search for on our Site, access
times and dates, and other statistics. We use this information to monitor and analyze use
of the Site and the Services and for the Site’s technical administration, to increase our
Site’s functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor it to our visitors’ needs. For
example, some of this information is collected so that when you visit the Site again, it will
recognize you and serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your
interests. We also use this information to verify that visitors to the Site meet the criteria
required to process their requests. We do not treat Log Data as Personal Information or
use it in association with other Personal Information, though we may aggregate, analyze
and evaluate such information to provide you with a better experience, to improve the
quality and value of the Site and to analyze and understand how our Site is used.
Cookies. We use “cookies” on our Site to collect information. A cookie is a small data file
that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use
cookies for two purposes. First, we utilize persistent cookies to save your search
preferences and Personal Information and registration ID and login password for future
use of the Site. Second, we utilize session ID cookies to enable certain features of the
Site, to better understand how you interact with the Site and to monitor aggregate usage
by our users and web traffic routing on the Site. Unlike persistent cookies, session
cookies are deleted from your computer when you leave or log off from the Site and then
close your browser. Third-party advertisers through the Site may also place or read
cookies on your browser. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop
accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit.
If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions or all
functionality of the Site.
Information Sharing and Disclosure
We do not share Personal Information with third parties except as follows:
        §    Service Providers. We may employ third party companies and individuals to
              facilitate the Services, to provide the Services on our behalf, to perform Site-
              related Services (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database
              management, web analytics and improvement of the Site’s features) or to assist
              us in analyzing how our Services are used. These third parties have access to
              your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are
              obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.
        §    Aggregate Information. We may share aggregated information that does not
              include Personal Information and we may otherwise disclose aggregated Usage
              Information and Log Data with third parties (including suppliers, advertisers,
              research companies and other organizations) for industry analysis, demographic
© 2015 metaio GmbH • Worldwide: +49 89 5480 198-0 • USA: +1 415 814-3376 • email: info@metaio.com 2
All information contained in this document is confidential and proprietary

www.metaio.com
              profiling and other purposes. Any information shared in these contexts will not
              contain your Personal Information.
        §    Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement. metaio cooperates with government
              and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the
              law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement
              officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or
              appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to
              subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of metaio or a third party, to protect
              the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may
              consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, any illegal, unethical or legally
              actionable activity.
        §    Business Transfers. We may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of our
              assets, including your Personal Information, in connection with a merger,
              acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy.
Changing or Deleting Your Information
All registered users may review, update, correct or delete their Personal Information by
contacting us or by making the appropriate modifications in your user account
preferences through the Site and/or the Products and/or the metaio Developer Portal. If
you completely delete all such information, then your account may become deactivated.
If you would like us to delete your record in our system, please contact us and we will
attempt to accommodate your request if we do not have any legal obligation to retain the
record.
Security
metaio is very concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ administrative,
physical and electronic measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized
access. We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security,
confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored “personal data” (as
defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or
conspicuous posting through the Services in the most expedient time possible and
without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law
enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and
restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.
International Transfer
Your information may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located in
countries within and outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) where the privacy
laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. Prior to such transfer, we will
endeavor to take reasonable steps to protect the privacy rights with respective to your
information. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such
information represents your agreement to that transfer.
Our Policy regarding Children
The Services is not directed to children under 15. We do not knowingly collect personally
identifiable information from children under 15. If a parent or guardian becomes aware
that their child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, contact
us and we will delete such information from our files. If we become aware that a child
under 15 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from
our files.
© 2015 metaio GmbH • Worldwide: +49 89 5480 198-0 • USA: +1 415 814-3376 • email: info@metaio.com   3
All information contained in this document is confidential and proprietary

www.metaio.com
Contacting Us
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at
privacy@metaio.com or at:
metaio GmbH
Infanteriestrasse 19
House 4b
D-80797 Munich
Germany
Effective June 26, 2013
© 2015 metaio GmbH • Worldwide: +49 89 5480 198-0 • USA: +1 415 814-3376 • email: info@metaio.com 4
All information contained in this document is confidential and proprietary
